Peter Buitenhuis fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Publications, 1958 - 2001; F-242-5; 4 cm of textual records
  - "Arnold Bennett: The Propagandist versus the Novelist." Clio 5 no. 2 (Winter), 151-174., 1976; F-242-5-0-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 242-6)
  - Review of Margaret Laurence: The Writer and Her Critics, edited by William New, 125-128., [ca 1977] - 1977; F-242-5-0-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 242-6)
  - "E.J. Pratt." In The Canadian Imagination: Dimensions of Literary Culture, ed. David Staines, 46-68. Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press., 1977; F-242-5-0-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 242-6)
  - Review of Narcissus and the Voyeur: Three Books and Two Films, by Robert M. MacLean, 382-385., [ca 1979] - 1979; F-242-5-0-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 242-6)
  - "The Stoic Strain in American Literature." In The Stoic Strain in American Literature: Essays in Honour of Marston LaFrance, ed. Duane J. MacMillan, 3-16. Toronto: University of Toronto Press., 1979; F-242-5-0-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 242-6)
  - "Henry James's 'The Art of Fiction' in its European Context." Revue Francaise D'Etudes Americaines 8, no. 17, 217-225., May 1983; F-242-5-0-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 242-7)
  - "Robert Kroetsch and the De-Mythologising of the Canadian West." In Canadiana: Studies in Canadian Literature, eds. J√∏rn Carlsen and Knud Larsen, 43-50. Aarhus, Denmark: Canadian Studies Conference, Department of English, University of Aarhus., 1984; F-242-5-0-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 242-7)
  - Review of Helmet of Flesh, by Scott Symons. The Reader 5, no. 2, 25-26., June 1986; F-242-5-0-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 242-7)
  - "Americans in European Gardens." The Henry James Review 7, no. 2-3 (Winter-Spring), 124-130., 1986; F-242-5-0-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 242-7)
  - Review of The Conformist, by Alberto Moravia. In Masterplots II: World Fiction Series vol. 1, ed. Frank N. Magill, 319-322. Pasadena, CA: Salem Press., 1987; F-242-5-0-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 242-7)
  - Review of The Cowards by Josef kvoreck. In Masterplots II: World Fiction Series vol. 1, ed. Frank N. Magill, 341-344. Pasadena, CA: Salem Press., 1987; F-242-5-0-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 242-7)
  - "Present Imperative: New Directions in Canadian Literary Theory." College English 50, no. 8, 927-930., December 1988; F-242-5-0-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 242-7)
  - "The Bittersweet Fruits of Exile: George Jonas and Josef kvoreck ." In Cross-Cultural Studies: American, Canadian and European Literatures, 1945-1985, ed. Mirko Jurak, 451-456. Ljubljana, Yugoslavia: English Department, Edvard Kardelj University of Ljubljana., 1988; F-242-5-0-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 242-7)
  - "Fatal Attractions; Miscegenation in the Literature of the Canadian North." Zeitschrift der Gesellschaft für Kanada-Studien 15, no. 1, 47-60., 1989; F-242-5-0-0-0-26 (Archival box - standard 242-7)
  - “Timothy Findley and the Theatre: An Interview.” West Coast Line 24, no. 2 (Fall), 109-111., 1990; F-242-5-0-0-0-27 (Archival box - standard 242-7)
  - “Jack Hodgins.” In Profiles in Canadian Literature, vol. 8, ed. Jeffery M. Heath, 99-105. Toronto: Dundurn Press., 1991; F-242-5-0-0-0-28 (Archival box - standard 242-7)
  - “Forging and Re-Forging the Canon of Canadian Literature.” In Venezia e i Caboto: Le Relazione Italo-Canadesi: Atti del Convegno Internazionale, Università di Venezia, 21-23 maggio 1990, eds. R. Mamoli Zorzi and U. Tucci, 155-162. Venice: Università Degli Studi di Venezia., 1992; F-242-5-0-0-0-29 (Archival box - standard 242-7)
  - Foundations of Canadian Culture: Canadian Studies 210-3 Course Reader, eds. Irwin Shubert, Peter Buitenhuis, and Ann Cowan. Burnaby, BC: Simon Fraser University, Centre for Distance Education., 1997; F-242-5-0-0-0-30 (Archival box - standard 242-7)
  - Foundations of Canadian Culture: Canadian Studies 210-3 Study Guide, eds. Irwin Shubert, Peter Buitenhuis, and Ann Cowan. Burnaby, BC: Simon Fraser University, Centre for Distance Education., 1997; F-242-5-0-0-0-31 (Archival box - standard 242-7)
  - “Ezra Pound: The Genius in the Bughouse.” Review of “I Cease Not to Yowl”: Ezra Pound’s Letters to Olivia Rossetti Agresti, eds. Demetres P. Tryphonopoulos and Leon Surette. Documentary Editing 21, no. 3 (September), 65-67., September 1999; F-242-5-0-0-0-32 (Archival box - standard 242-7)
  - “Motherhood Perverted: The Trope of the Son and the Front.” In Dressing Up for War: Transformations of Gender and Genre in the Discourse and Literature of War, eds. Aránzazu Usandizaga and Andrew Monnickendam, 13-25. New York: Rodopi., 2001; F-242-5-0-0-0-33 (Archival box - standard 242-7)
  - Times Literary Supplement (TLC) Review of "The Canadian Imagination", 1978; F-242-5-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 242-6)
  - "Comment and Response." College English, 102-106 / Thomas F. McKendy and Richard Coe, 1988., [ca 1988]; F-242-5-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 242-6)